<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC1423'>

<front>
<title abbrev='PEM: Algorithms, Modes and Identifiers'>Privacy Enhancement for Internet Electronic Mail: Part III: Algorithms, Modes, and Identifiers</title>
<author initials='D.' surname='Balenson' fullname='David Balenson'>
<organization>Trusted Information Systems</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>3060 Washington Road</street>
<city>Glenwood</city>
<region>MD</region>
<code>21738</code>
<country>US</country></postal>
<phone>+1 301 854 6889</phone>
<email>balenson@tis.com</email></address></author>
<date year='1993' month='February' />
<abstract>
<t>This document provides definitions, formats, references, and citations for cryptographic algorithms, usage modes, and associated identifiers and parameters used in support of Privacy Enhanced Mail (PEM) in the Internet community.  It is intended to become one member of the set of related PEM RFCs.  This document is organized into four primary sections, dealing with message encryption algorithms, message integrity check algorithms, symmetric key management algorithms, and asymmetric key management algorithms (including both asymmetric encryption and asymmetric signature algorithms).</t>
<t>Some parts of this material are cited by other documents and it is anticipated that some of the material herein may be changed, added, or replaced without affecting the citing documents.  Therefore, algorithm-specific material has been placed into this separate document.</t>
<t>Use of other algorithms and/or modes will require case-by-case study to determine applicability and constraints.  The use of additional algorithms may be documented first in Prototype or Experimental RFCs. As experience is gained, these protocols may be considered for incorporation into the standard.  Additional algorithms and modes approved for use in PEM in this context will be specified in successors to this document.</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='1423' />
<format type='TXT' octets='33277' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc1423.txt' />
</reference>
