<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>

<reference anchor='RFC2434'>

<front>
<title abbrev='Guidelines for IANA Considerations'>Guidelines for Writing an IANA Considerations Section in RFCs</title>
<author initials='T.' surname='Narten' fullname='Thomas Narten'>
<organization>IBM Corporation</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>3039 Cornwallis Ave.</street>
<street>PO Box 12195 - BRQA/502</street>
<street>Research Triangle Park</street>
<street>NC 27709-2195</street></postal>
<phone>919-254-7798</phone>
<email>narten@raleigh.ibm.com</email></address></author>
<author initials='H.T.' surname='Alvestrand' fullname='Harald Tveit Alvestrand'>
<organization>Maxware</organization>
<address>
<postal>
<street>Pirsenteret</street>
<street>N-7005 Trondheim</street>
<country>Norway</country></postal>
<phone>+47 73 54 57 97</phone>
<email>Harald@Alvestrand.no</email></address></author>
<date year='1998' month='October' />
<area>General</area>
<keyword>Internet Assigned Numbers Authority</keyword>
<keyword>IANA</keyword>
<abstract>
<t>
   Many protocols make use of identifiers consisting of constants and
   other well-known values. Even after a protocol has been defined and
   deployment has begun, new values may need to be assigned (e.g., for a
   new option type in DHCP, or a new encryption or authentication
   algorithm for IPSec).  To insure that such quantities have consistent
   values and interpretations in different implementations, their
   assignment must be administered by a central authority. For IETF
   protocols, that role is provided by the Internet Assigned Numbers
   Authority (IANA).
</t>
<t>
   In order for the IANA to manage a given name space prudently, it
   needs guidelines describing the conditions under which new values can
   be assigned. If the IANA is expected to play a role in the management
   of a name space, the IANA must be given clear and concise
   instructions describing that role.  This document discusses issues
   that should be considered in formulating a policy for assigning
   values to a name space and provides guidelines to document authors on
   the specific text that must be included in documents that place
   demands on the IANA.
</t></abstract></front>

<seriesInfo name='BCP' value='26' />
<seriesInfo name='RFC' value='2434' />
<format type='TXT' octets='25092' target='http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc2434.txt' />
<format type='XML' octets='27060' target='http://xml.resource.org/public/rfc/xml/rfc2434.xml' />
</reference>
